thinking back to it, because my memory of it is it
was like a plywood deck hanging from the ceiling.
Vanessa:
Did it have a-
Dan:
It was hanging down, and you climbed a ladder up
to it. It had plywood walls, but there were gaps
in the walls too, where you could just jump down,
which we didn't jump down. But what we did was
because it was a one room cabin, if my parents
were there with some friends or my grandparents,
they would play cards, and they would send us to
bed, but we could hear everything, so we'd spy on
them and we'd drop stuff down on them and stuff.
Vanessa:
That sounds fun.
Dan:
Yeah. That was fun.
Vanessa:
Wow, so maybe we can recreate this
rustic experience.
Dan:
We need a loft.
Vanessa:
Do you think it would be just as fun as
an adult? Because you were a kid doing it,
do you think that-
Dan:
To sleep in the loft?
Vanessa:
Well, for us, because we're adults now, so
having this rural experience, would it be as
fun for us as it would-
Dan:
I think it would be.
Vanessa:
... as for kids?
Dan:
Yeah, because one benefit of being in a place like
America and the United States is that you can
usually find some place that is very rural
and quiet.
Vanessa:
Quickly and close.
Dan:
We live close enough to a highway
and stuff that it would be nice to
just only hear the birds chirping.
Vanessa:
Yeah. I think that's really possible. I mean-
Dan:
And get away from electronics and stuff. It would
have to be an intentional, this is not a place
where we have a TV, for example.
Vanessa:
Yeah. I think you can drive about 20 minutes away
from our house and be very much in the woods.
Dan:
Yes.
Vanessa:
But anyway, that's a
specific discussion for another time.
Dan:
Yes.
Vanessa:
Cool. So, you'd like to have-
Dan:
More property.
Vanessa:
... a cabin, and that would be a investment,
an investment that you could justify.
Well, I think for me, when I thought about this,
I thought more of something that we already do
that we have justified spending more money on, so-
Dan:
Garden boxes.
Vanessa:
I spend too much money on the garden. That's true.
These are the world's most expensive tomatoes.
Dan:
We are now a small scale farm.
Vanessa:
That's not what I was saying, but that
is true. I thought of something more
in our daily life. I think this is different for
everyone depending on how much money you have. At
some point in our marriage, we bought the cheapest
food. This is all that we could afford and
that was it. But then as we made more money, we
wanted to intentionally buy better quality food.
Dan:
We prioritize it.
Vanessa:
Yeah. So, instead
of just buying expensive food, we wanted to buy,
especially we kind of made an intention to buy
better quality animal products specifically. In
the US, you have a lot of options. You could buy
organic carrots or conventional carrots, and
not so much that I'm thinking more about meat
and yogurt and cheese and milk-
Dan:
Where the creatures are involved.
Vanessa:
Yeah, because in the area where we live,
there's a lot of options for buying
local grass fed beef, for example, where
there's a farm down the street and it's
much more expensive than buying the cheapest
beef at the grocery store. But for us,
as we've made more money, this has been
something that we justify spending more money on.
If we didn't have money, then I would not spend
money on that, because that wasn't a priority.