Vanessa Hi I'm Vanessa from SpeakEnglishWithVanessa com
Today I have a special guest my husband Dan Dan Hello Vanessa
Today we are going to be having a long English conversation
because over two years ago back in February 2020 we made this conversation
and millions of you loved this and said that it helped you to immerse yourself in English and have a fun time
Today we are going to be doing something similar
We'll be talking about at least 10 possibly more topics
We'll be giving our opinions and stories and ideas Dan Answers Vanessa
Yes whatever comes up along the way
There will be subtitles for key phrases down here
but you can also click CC to get the full subtitles
so that you don't miss any words
All right are you ready to get started Dan I'm ready Vanessa Let's do it
But wait before we get started like always I have created a free PDF worksheet for this lesson that you can download
Never forget what you are about to learn
You can click on the link in the description to download this free PDF worksheet today
and you will have a chance to answer all of today's questions too Dan